const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",o=200,n=120,a=[{id:333,question:"A  trade  group for insurance  companies in  Nigeria is called",option:{a:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",b:"National Insurance Commission",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"Nigerian Insurers Association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:335,question:"Who  among  the  following  is  an  employer  of  loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:82,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Peril",c:"Hazard",d:"Moral"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:216,question:"With assurance contract there is",option:{a:"uncertainly of reward",b:"certainty of reward",c:"certainty of occurrence",d:"uncertainty of occurrence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:76,question:"The following are insurable except",option:{a:"Marine",b:"Goods",c:"Gambling",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:337,question:"The  document issued by  the  insurer when there is a change in the particulars of a risk insured is",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"certificate",c:"voucher",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:258,question:"One of the following is necessary to meet uncertainties in future",option:{a:"profit",b:"capital",c:"borrowing",d:"insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:225,question:"The process of evaluating and minimizing risk is",option:{a:"risk management",b:"risk certainty",c:"risk insurance",d:"risk re-grouping"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:2,question:"One of the objectives of buying a term assurance policy is to",option:{a:"protect  dependants  in  case  of  death  of  the  life assured",b:"reduce financial burden of the life assured",c:"supplement retirement income  of  the  life  assured",d:"maximize savings from the life assured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:318,question:"The policy that covers  an  insured  employee  against injury  sustained  in  the  course  of  employment  is",option:{a:"professional indemnity",b:"product liability",c:"public liability",d:"employer’s liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:326,question:"What is the full meaning of “NCRIB” in the insurance industry?",option:{a:"National  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",b:"Nigerian  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"National Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:93,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"aviation policy",b:"engineering policy",c:"life policy",d:"marine policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:38,question:"Effective supervision and licensing of insurance firms in Nigeria is the function of",option:{a:"National Insurance Commission",b:"Institute of Loss Adjusters of Nigeria",c:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",d:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:85,question:"Transfer of rights and liabilities under a contract with the consent of the other party is known as",option:{a:"Assignment",b:"liability",c:"Interest",d:"Legality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:118,question:"The principle of subrogation imposed an obligation on the insured to",option:{a:"Disclose all material information",b:"Have financial risks in the object",c:"Press for compensation",d:"Surrender legal right after compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:260,question:"If the insured has been fully indemnified, the insurers are entitled to take any advantage due to the insured. Principle of insurance involved is",option:{a:"insurable interest",b:"contribution",c:"indemnity",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:170,question:"The type of questionnaire drawn up by   insurers, requesting certain information to assess risk is --------- form",option:{a:"Acceptance",b:"Compensation",c:"Credit",d:"Proposal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:185,question:"In insurance contract, failure to disclose all relevant material facts will render the contract",option:{a:"legal",b:"Voidable",c:"Void",d:"Implied"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following factors limits indemnity?",option:{a:"Cession",b:"Re - insurance",c:"Excess",d:"Co - insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:171,question:"The shifting of responsibility of one’s own losses to another is known as ---------- transfer",option:{a:"Fund",b:"Risk",c:"Business",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:44,question:"Insurers A and B cover a risk at the ratio of 2:5 for the sum insured of N= 1,800. How much would insurer  A get from the risk?",option:{a:"N= 1,285.00",b:"N= 771.00",c:"N= 514.00",d:"N= 180.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:192,question:"The process of changing anything wrong with the policy to make it current is",option:{a:"Endorsement",b:"Specification",c:"Rectification",d:"Correction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:158,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Peril",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:233,question:"Proposal form is used in the following classes of insurance except",option:{a:"Accident",b:"theft",c:"life",d:"large risk of fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:293,question:"The form of risk that can easily be calculated and estimated is known as",option:{a:"non insurable risk",b:"non-financial risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"insurable risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:191,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"21 days",b:"one month",c:"12 months",d:"3 month"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:296,question:"The maximum number of days allowed for a policy holder to pay his renewal premium after it has become due is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"conditions",c:"days of grace",d:"days of liberty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:210,question:"Occurrence of an unplanned event is called",option:{a:"hazard",b:"loss",c:"risk",d:"speculation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:161,question:"------------- is a policy designed to place the insured in the same financial position as he was immediately before the happening of the event insured against",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subrogation",c:"Surrender value",d:"Actuary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:162,question:"The essential value of valid contract that states that the parties to a contract must be in perfect agreement and have a common mind is",option:{a:"Consideration",b:"Perpetual existence",c:"Excess",d:"Consensus ad-idem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:153,question:"The provider of protection to an insurance  company against the excess risk it has given insurance covers is called",option:{a:"Assurer",b:"Insuring",c:"Reinsurer",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:329,question:"The  sum  insured  for  a  risk  is  N= 150,000  and  was accepted  for  fire  insurance at a rate of  0.25%. How much will the insured pay as a premium?",option:{a:"N= 125",b:"N= 375",c:"N= 500",d:"N= 875"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:148,question:"The deliberate or intentional throwing over board of part of a cargo to lighten the ship in the interest of the reminder of the cargo is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Jettison",c:"Breach",d:"Caveat emptor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:187,question:"The insurance principle which implies that a proof is required that the direct and immediate cause of the loss suffered was by the occurrence of the risk insured against is called",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Insurable interest",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:237,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"insurance register",c:"insurance green card",d:"Ecowas brown card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:193,question:"A syndicate or an insurance company that transfer risk under re-insurance is",option:{a:"Cede",b:"Cession",c:"Commutation",d:"Cedant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:269,question:"To which of the following does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"the insurer only",b:"the proposer only",c:"the third party and insured",d:"insurer and proposer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following activities is not involved in claims management?",option:{a:"Proof of loss",b:"Particulars of loss",c:"Premium calculation",d:"Primary investigation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:268,question:"The payment made when the insured is not entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:133,question:"When an insured person admits that he has indemnified, he means that",option:{a:"The damage proper by has been recovered",b:"He was paid premium fully",c:"The insurance company has restored him to his former position",d:"He was paid his premium fully"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:306,question:"Which of the following is the function of a loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Ensures payment of adequate compensation",b:"Advises the insurer on claim",c:"Operates with unlimited authority",d:"Notifies insurer of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:146,question:"Workman compensation is also referred to as",option:{a:"Fidelity insurance",b:"Employment liability",c:"Public liability",d:"Product liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:128,question:"The continuation of insurance contract after expiration is",option:{a:"Renewal",b:"Revival",c:"Resuscitation",d:"Rejuvenation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:305,question:"The payment by an insurer to the insured in the event of loss is",option:{a:"claim",b:"premium",c:"fee",d:"interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:347,question:"Which of the following is a duty of an insured in an insurance contract?",option:{a:"Concealment of facts",b:"Exposure of facts",c:"Disclosure of facts",d:"Acceptance of facts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:208,question:"An undertaking by the insured that certain things shall be done or not be done or certain things shall be put in place or not in place is called",option:{a:"warranties and representation",b:"utmost good faith and uberrimae fidei",c:"insurable and non-insurable",d:"subrogation and indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:316,question:"Educational endowment policy is designed to protect the interest of",option:{a:"father",b:"mother",c:"child",d:"uncle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:221,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"voidable contract",b:"legal contract",c:"void contract",d:"valid contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:188,question:"Method of providing indemnity whereby subject matter is being restored to its former position is",option:{a:"Repairs",b:"Cash",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:172,question:"A financial compensation sufficient to return the insured back to his original position after loss is known as",option:{a:"Deposit",b:"Loan",c:"Indemnity",d:"Overdraft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:297,question:"The  factor  that has  the  tendency  to  increase  the occurrence of a risk is called",option:{a:"risk",b:"loss",c:"hazard",d:"peril"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:59,question:"In insurance contract offeree is the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance company",c:"client",d:"Third party"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:42,question:"A voucher signed by the insured before collecting his claim is",option:{a:"money collect receipt",b:"discharge voucher",c:"payment receipt",d:"pay - in - slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:273,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:254,question:"If the insured does not want the contract to continue he receives",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"consideration",c:"premium",d:"commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:288,question:"Marine  losses are divided into",option:{a:"actual total and total loss",b:"total loss and partial loss",c:"partial loss and actual loss",d:"average loss and partial loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:12,question:"A prospective insured in an engineering insurance may be advised to purchase one of the following classes of insurance",option:{a:"fire cover",b:"boiler cover",c:"tempest cover",d:"equipment cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:217,question:"Indemnity is not applicable in",option:{a:"assurance contract",b:"insurance contract",c:"insurance terms",d:"insurance content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:304,question:"In which of the following classes of insurance is no <em>claim discount</em> applicable?",option:{a:"Money insurance",b:"Marine insurance",c:"Motor insurance",d:"Aviation insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:3,question:"An assurance policy taken by experts to cover possible negligence arising from their duties is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"professional indemnity",c:"cargo",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:276,question:"The contract aimed at providing specific payment at regular intervals for a fixed   period or for life is",option:{a:"accident",b:"annuity",c:"average",d:"term"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:163,question:"A  Statement signed by the insured, certifying the Statement",option:{a:"Certificate",b:"Declaration",c:"Confirmation slip",d:"Accuracy statement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:40,question:"The owner of a life assurance policy who enters into an agreement to sell the ownership of the policy and beneficiary rights upon the death of the insured is called",option:{a:"an underwriter",b:"a aviator",c:"a factor",d:"an assessor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:70,question:"Which of this is an odd one out?",option:{a:"offer and acceptance",b:"contractual capacity",c:"legality of object",d:"Adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:7,question:"In  classification  of  risks, what is the name given to a risk  where  the  causes  of  events are linked to factors 	that are due to the society we live in?",option:{a:"Dynamic risk",b:"Particular risk",c:"Speculative risk",d:"Fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:72,question:"The risks which affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"static",c:"fundamental",d:"speculative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:270,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of policy",d:"resolution of dispute"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:307,question:"A fire insurance policy guaranteed by the insured to be in place for a stated period with a particular insurer is granted a _____________",option:{a:"no claim discount",b:"fleet discount",c:"long - term agreement discount",d:"plurality discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:54,question:"The facts which might influence any party’s willingness to enter the contract or reject it is called",option:{a:"insurable fact",b:"insurance fact",c:"insured fact",d:"material fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:202,question:"In a contract of insurance, a firm statement is usually made by a person known as the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"insur",d:"client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:178,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Commission",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:18,question:"How  much  premium  will  the  insurer  return  to  the insured?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:266,question:"One of this is the evidence of insurance contract",option:{a:"schedule",b:"policy",c:"proposal form",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:336,question:"The meaning of with <em>profit policy</em>  in life assurance is that the sum assured is paid",option:{a:"without profit",b:"with profit",c:"with interest",d:"without interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:101,question:"When someone is placed back in the same financial position that he was in just prior to a loss, that is ----",option:{a:"Actual cash value",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:10,question:"Which of the following is a contract of benefit?",option:{a:"Personal accident insurance",b:"Business interruption insurance",c:"Fire insurance",d:"Money insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:22,question:"One of the information contained in a motor insurance cover note is the",option:{a:"behaviour of the insured",b:"occupation of the insured",c:"commencement date",d:"previous and present insurance history"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:121,question:"Insurance is necessary because of the need to",option:{a:"Pool resources together",b:"Meet uncertainties in future",c:"Make profit",d:"Lend money to individual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:236,question:"Which of the method below can be used to provide indemnity in the event of loss",option:{a:"moral advice",b:"resolution of policy",c:"cash payment",d:"professional encouragement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:328,question:"The cover that is taken at the option of the motor vehicle owner is",option:{a:"a comprehensive cover",b:"an act only cover",c:"a third party only cover",d:"a special type cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:248,question:"The type of cover for violent and forcible entry into a premises is called",option:{a:"burglary and theft",b:"third party fire and theft",c:"third party and theft",d:"stealing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:255,question:"Re-insurance means",option:{a:"accumulation of risk",b:"multiplication of risk",c:"transfer of risk",d:"adding of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:242,question:"A written amendment in addition or alterations to the information stated in the policy is called",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"specification",c:"construction",d:"attestation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:17,question:"How much premium will the insurer charge?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:234,question:"The following classes of insurance apply the use of proposal form except",option:{a:"public liability",b:"large risk of marine insurance",c:"small risk of marine insurance",d:"theft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:127,question:"Re-insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Re-insurer and insurer",b:"Re- insurance and insurance",c:"Co-insurer and insurer",d:"Insurance broker and re-insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:157,question:"------------ is used to bring amendment in a policy that is either to add in a new thing or removal of an existing thing in the policy",option:{a:"Excess",b:"Endorsement",c:"Claim form",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:300,question:"One of these is a full time professional",option:{a:"broker",b:"agent",c:"factor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:195,question:"Application by the insured to the insurer for the payment of money due under his contract of insurance is",option:{a:"Proof",b:"Evidence",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:62,question:"The temporary document issued by the insurer to the insured while the policy is being prepared is",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"promissory note",c:"exchange slip",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:339,question:"Which of the following documents forms the basis of a contract in insurance business?",option:{a:"Policy document",b:"Proposal form",c:"Claim form",d:"Discharge form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:280,question:"An  attempt  to  deprive  someone of his  property is",option:{a:"theft",b:"burglary",c:"robbery",d:"larceny"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:184,question:"The principle that requires all material facts to be disclosed is known as",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Fidelity",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:97,question:"A formal document containing the condition of the insurance contract is called",option:{a:"agreement",b:"contract form",c:"contract slip",d:"policy document"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:53,question:"An insurance principle that requires the insured to be honest and disclose all relevant facts is called",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"proximate cause",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:223,question:"Which of the following cannot enter into an insurance contract?",option:{a:"adult",b:"insured",c:"minor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:142,question:"Amount paid to the beneficiary upon the death of the insured is",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Compensation",c:"Declaration",d:"Death benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:139,question:"Consequential loss is also known as",option:{a:"Business interruption insurance",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Excess loss",d:"Property insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:317,question:"A clause in an insurance policy that makes a claim jointly payable to the policyholder and the third party is",option:{a:"claim clause",b:"mortgagee clause",c:"mortgage clause",d:"joint liability clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:348,question:"The principle of maritime law which makes owners of a ship and cargo share in a loss incurred voluntarily is",option:{a:"special average",b:"general average",c:"specific average",d:"particular average"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:182,question:"A professional officer of an insurance company whose duty among others is to calculate the premium to be 	paid by the insured is called",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Principal",c:"Actuarist",d:"Adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:73,question:"Risks that are peculiar to an individual actions and decision is known as",option:{a:"fundamental risk",b:"particular risk",c:"pure risk",d:"speculative risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:265,question:"Which of the following risks is covered by insurance policy?",option:{a:"an investment loss on the stock market",b:"dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"failure of a business venture",d:"rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:319,question:"What is  the  maximum  liability which the insurer can pay on a particular loss?",option:{a:"Average",b:"Sum insured",c:"Franchise",d:"Excess"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:140,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"motor",b:"Life",c:"Marine",d:"Aviation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"}],t={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,t as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,n as total};
